Roy Emmanuel S. Medina

PROFILE

Entry level Data Engineer with experience designing manufacturing database schemas and developing data transformation pipelines to create dashboards, screens, and reports. Background in planning and executing the development of business software applications for data collection, reporting, and analysis in a medical device manufacturing environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dexcom – Data Analyst

(February 2020 – Present)

- Use statistical programming languages to run statistical analysis on manufacturing production data
- Develop Web Applications to collect, store, and transform manufacturing data for data collection, reporting, and analysis
- Designed, developed, and trained end users on data collection applications used to enhance diagnostic dashboards
- Create programs to extract, transform, and load datasets from multiple Microsoft servers onto enterprise cloud platforms
- Collaborate with internal teams to fulfill cross-functional tasks

University of San Diego – Student Hardware and Software Lead

(August 2019 – May 2020)

- Prepare and provide training on enterprise IT equipment troubleshooting and information workflow processes
- Develop and document standard procedures to identify and resolve hardware and software issues

University of San Diego – Student Technician

(August 2018 – August 2019)

- Manage phone calls from the campus community and assist in troubleshooting hardware and software issues
- Hands-on troubleshoot, diagnosis, and repairs on computers and devices of campus's community members
- Document and record IT incidents and requests

Data Analyst

Data Engineer

Industrial and Systems Engineer

CONTACT

- **2** (619)-212-1397
- ♠ El Cajon, CA 92019

SKILLS

 $(\bullet = 1 \text{ year of experience})$

Software Languages

Python
SQL
R
HTML/CSS
JavaScript
Java
C++

Software

MS Office Suite
Linux Terminal
Tableau

••••

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

University of San Diego

2017 - 2021

BS/BA, Industrial and Systems Engineering GPA: 3.52

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

2020

Issuer: University of San Diego